[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
So for handling non-coordinate data, non-numerical data,
对于无坐标数据 和非数值量的数据
we're often more interested in the relationship between data
比起数据本身来说 我们常常对数据之间的关系
items than in the data items themselves.
更感兴趣
And so we'll use a graph or
所以我们用图
a network to represent the relationships between data items.
或者网状图来表示数据间的关系
And so we'll talk here about different ways of specifying a graph, and
这里我们要讨论的是 指明图的不同方式
different attributes of graphs, and how graphs are represented computationally.
图的不同属性 以及如何以计算方式来表示图
So a graph just consists of nodes and edges.
图由点和边组成
In this case, we have four nodes and we have five edges connecting these nodes.
本例中有四个顶点 和五条边把点连接起来
And so the nodes will represent a data item and
这些节点表示数据项
the edge will represent a relationship between two data items.
边表示数据项之间有关联
If we add this particular edge,
如果我们加上这一条边
then every data item is going to be connected to every other data item.
每个数据项 都会和其他数据项相连
We would call that a complete graph, or a clique, of these four nodes.
这叫做完全图，或者一个团 由4个顶点组成的团
Here on the left, I've got I've got a graph of four nodes connected by
左图中 4个顶点由5条边连接
five edges, and on the right I've got four nodes connected by five edges.
右图中4个顶点也由5条边连接
In fact, these two graphs are isomorphic.
事实上 这两个图是同构的
They're the same graph, they're just laid out differently.
它们是同一个图 只是布局方式不同
And on the right, I've got a planar graph, which means to nodes and
右图是一个平面图 意思是说
edges are laid out so that none of the edges cross each other.
每个顶点和边都平面分布 不会与其他边相交
And then I can speak of a face as being the region bounded
面指的是被一系列边 组成的环围成的区域
by a cycle of edges starting and ending at the same node.
边的开始和结束都在同一个点
And also, we would say that these are two different embeddings
我们说，这是对同一个图的 两种显示方式
of the same graph or at least these graphs are isomorphic.
或者说两个图是同构的
If we think of this whole arrangement of eight nodes and
如果把这8个顶点和十条边
ten edges as a single graph,
看作一整个图
then that would be one graph consisting of two connected components, but
那么这个图含有两个连通分量
the entire graph containing both of these sub graphs would be a disconnected graph.
但整个图并不是一个连通图
We can also have directed graphs.
也存在有向图
So in an ordinary graph, or an undirected graph,
在一个普通图 或者无向图中
just has edges, but does not really suggest the direction of these edges.
是有边的 但并不代表会指示边的方向
We can have a directed graph by using arrows to indicate a direction, so
我们可以用箭头来代表方向 组成有向图
that we would have a connection from this node to this node, but
这样如果从一个点 到另一个点有连接
not necessarily a connection from this node back to this node.
但反过来不一定有连接
And you can think of a graph as having a cycle, a directed graph having a cycle, so
有向图中可能会有环
this undirected graph, this ordinary graph has a cycle because these three nodes.
无向图中也可能会有环 这里的环由3个点组成
I can start at this node and I can follow the cycle to get back.
我可以从这个点开始 跟着环返回这个点
You can have a cyclic directed graph, because I can follow a cycle here.
这就是一个带环有向图 因为我可以跟着这个环返回
This graph is acyclic, because there is no cycle.
这个图则是无环图 因为图里没有环
Once I get to this node I can go to this node.
如果从这个点开始 我可以走到这个点
Once I get to this node, I can't go any place further.
但当我到这个点时 就不能去别的点了
So there's no way to get back to any of these nodes
如果跟着这些方向的话
by following these edges in the directions indicated.
无法回到其他的点上
You can also have trees.
也可以有树形结构
Any graph that's connected
每一个连通的图
that has one less edge than the number of nodes forms a tree.
如果边数比点数要少一 就形成了树
It's minimally connected.
这是最小连通的
And you can think of having a parent node, but for an undirected graph,
你可以认为里面有一个父节点 但对于无向图而言
any of these nodes could be the parent and you can think of multiple siblings.
每个点都可以称为父结点 你可以认为有好几个兄弟结点
Here's some graphs with many more edges and
这里有一些有更多边的图
you can see kind of the way they're laid out would imply a parent.
可以从它们的布局看出 这已经表明里面有一个父节点
But I could lay these out in isomorphic methods,
但我也可以用其他 同构的方式来显示
equivalent methods, and another potent node might appear to be the parent.
这些方式是等价的 另一个点也可以成为父节点
When you have directed graphs, the tree forms a hierarchy and
在有向图中 树会显示出层级关系
then you can have a parent.
这样就会有父节点的存在
So in this case, the child nodes, these child nodes point to their parents.
这种情况下 子节点指向父节点
And so I've plotted their parents higher than the child nodes.
因此我把父节点 画的比子节点要高
And then there is a clear root node.
而根节点也非常清楚
This one parent that's the parent of all of these nodes.
它是所有节点的父节点
You can also have a hierarchy that's not a tree.
也可以有树以外的层级关系
In this case we have a parent relationship,
本例中有父子关系
but this child node has two parents.
但子节点有两个父节点
And so you've got a definite hierarchy here, but
虽然你有确定的层级关系 但是这不是树
it's not a tree because a tree would have each node would have a single parent node.
因为在树中每个节点 只能有一个父节点
There's also a relationship between
每个点具有的边的数量
the number of edges each node has and the kind of graph you're looking at.
也和图的类型有关
We talk about the degree of the node as being the number of edges
从一个点伸出的边的数量
extending from a node.
叫做度
Directed graphs would have a different in degree than an out degree.
有向图的入度和出度是不同的
The in degree would be the number of edges going into the node and
入度指的是到达点的边的数量
the out degree would be the number of edges leaving the node.
出度指的是 从点出发的边的数量
And then these, the number of nodes you have of each degree,
如果每个点具有的度
if it follows this kind of fall off, it's called a social network.
服从这样的分布 这叫社交网络图
A social network, you can think of this as a friend's network or
你可以认为社交网络是 朋友关系组成的网络
many natural
或者其他
data relationships follow this power law, this social network power law.
服从这种分布的自然关系网络 这种分布叫做社交网络幂律
In this case, this is the number of interactions of yeast proteins.
本例是酵母蛋白质的互作用
Each one of these nodes is a yeast protein, and
每个节点都是一个酵母蛋白质
the edges represent interaction between these proteins and, in this case,
而边代表的是蛋白质 之间的互作用关系
you have many nodes that have a few interactions that are connected to,
有很多节点之间 的互作用并不多
you know, one or two, you have one or two edges.
它们只有一或者两条边
And then you have many fewer nodes that have high degree, that have a lot of edges
有一些结点的度比较高 有很多边
that are connected to a lot of other nodes by a single edge.
连到很多其他的点上
And so in this case, the number of nodes that have a certain degree
这种情况下 具有一定度数的点
follows a power-law.
服从幂律关系
If the y is the number of nodes with that degree,
如果y指的是 具有一定度数的点的数量
is equal to the degree to some power with some constant multiplied to it.
那么它等于度数的某个幂 乘以一个常数
And you see this fall off happen quite often.
你会常常看见这种下降趋势
These graphs tend not to be plainer, they tend to be difficult to embed.
这些图常常不是平面的 它们很难平面化
They also tend to be the most popular graphs that we encounter in real life.
这也是我们在现实生活中 最常见的图
Finally, we're going to use an adjacency matrix to represent graphs.
最后我们来用 传递矩阵来表示图
And so in this case we have a graph that has four nodes, four data items.
本例中我们有4个顶点 代表4个数据项
One, two, three and four,
一 二 三和四
and then we're going to represent this graph using this matrix.
我们来用这个矩阵表示此图
In this case, the Adjacency Matrix will have a one in row one,
如果节点1到节点2之间 有边连接
column two, if there's an edge connecting node one to node two.
那么，在第1行第2列中 相邻矩阵的值是1
Likewise, it'll have a one in row two, column one,
同样的 如果第2行第1列的值为1
because it connects node two to node one and so it will be symmetric.
那么节点2到节点1是连接的 这样矩阵就对称了
Because this is a non-directed graph.
因为这是一个无向图
If it was a directed graph, then you would connect, if it was directed from
如果是有向图的话 从节点1到节点2
node one to node two by an edge leaving node one going to node two.
有一条边连接
Then you would have a one in row one column two but
这样第1行第2列的值为一 但是
you would have a zero in row two column one.
在第2行第1列的值为零
So a directed graph would have asymmetric or
所以有向图可能是不对称的或者
could have an asymmetric adjacency matrix but an ordinary graph,
它可能有不对称的相邻矩阵 但普通的图
a non-directed graph, would just have a symmetric adjacency matrix.
也就是无向图 会有对称的相邻矩阵
And these edges could also have weights,
边也可能有权重
in which case you might not just have zero or one, you might have a value here
这种情况下可能不只有0或1 而可能是一个值
to indicate how strong the connection is between nodes.
用来表示节点之间的连接强度
And the diagonal is usually zero, unless there's some relationship between a node
对角线上一般是零 除非节点和它本身之间有关系
and itself, and you can represent that along the diagonal.
这样你可以 在对角线上表示出来
So it might be good to review graphs and the different kinds of graphs,
对图的复习很有用 复习不同类型的图
the different representations of graphs, and
以不同方式表示图 还有图的不同属性
the different attributes of graphs to familiarize yourself with them,
会让你对它们更熟悉
because we'll be using those for the rest of this module.
因为本模块中 我们会用到这些知识
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community